We are losing our listening.
[AI] 我们正在失去听力。
We spend roughly 60 percent of our communication time listening.
[AI] 我们大约60%的交流时间都花在倾听上。
but we're not very good at it.
[AI] 但我们不是很擅长。
We retain just 25 percent of what we hear.
[AI] 我们只保留了25%的听力。
Now -- not you. not this talk.
[AI] 现在，不是你。不是这个话题。
but that is generally true.
[AI] 但这通常是正确的。
Let's define listening as making meaning from sound.
[AI] 让我们把倾听定义为从声音中产生意义。
It's a mental process.
[AI] 这是一个心理过程。
and it's a process of extraction.
[AI] 这是一个提取的过程。
We use some pretty cool techniques to do this.
[AI] 我们使用一些非常酷的技术来实现这一点。
One of them is pattern recognition.
[AI] 其中之一是模式识别。
(Crowd noises) So in a cocktail party like this.
[AI] （人群的喧闹声）在这样的鸡尾酒会上。
if I say. "David. Sara. pay attention" -- some of you just sat up.
[AI] 如果我说。“大卫，莎拉，注意”——你们有些人只是坐了起来。
We recognize patterns to distinguish noise from signal.
[AI] 我们识别模式以区分噪声和信号。
and especially our name.
[AI] 尤其是我们的名字。
Differencing is another technique we use.
[AI] 差分是我们使用的另一种技术。
If I left this pink noise on for more than a couple of minutes.
[AI] 如果我让这个粉红色的噪音持续几分钟以上。
(Pink noise) you would literally cease to hear it.
[AI] （粉红色的噪音）你真的听不见了。
We listen to differences; we discount sounds that remain the same.
[AI] 我们倾听差异；我们对保持不变的声音打折。
And then there is a whole range of filters.
[AI] 还有一系列的过滤器。
These filters take us from all sound
[AI] 这些过滤器使我们远离所有声音
down to what we pay attention to.
[AI] 具体到我们所关注的。
Most people are entirely unconscious of these filters.
[AI] 大多数人完全没有意识到这些过滤器。
But they actually create our reality in a way.
[AI] 但他们实际上以某种方式创造了我们的现实。
because they tell us what we're paying attention to right now.
[AI] 因为他们告诉我们我们现在关注的是什么。
I'll give you one example of that.
[AI] 我给你举个例子。
Intention is very important in sound. in listening.
[AI] 意图在声音中非常重要。在倾听中。
When I married my wife.
[AI] 当我和我妻子结婚的时候。
I promised her I would listen to her every day
[AI] 我答应她我会每天听她的
as if for the first time.
[AI] 好像是第一次。
Now that's something I fall short of on a daily basis.
[AI] 这是我每天都做不到的。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
But it's a great intention to have in a relationship.
[AI] 但这是一个伟大的意图在一段关系。
But that's not all.
[AI] 但这还不是全部。
Sound places us in space and in time.
[AI] 声音将我们置于时空之中。
If you close your eyes right now in this room.
[AI] 如果你现在在这个房间闭上眼睛。
you're aware of the size of the room
[AI] 你知道房间的大小
from the reverberation and the bouncing of the sound off the surfaces;
[AI] 从混响和表面反弹的声音；
you're aware of how many people are around you.
[AI] 你知道你周围有多少人。
because of the micro-noises you're receiving.
[AI] 因为你收到的是微小的噪音。
And sound places us in time as well.
[AI] 声音也能让我们及时到达目的地。
because sound always has time embedded in it.
[AI] 因为声音总是有时间在里面。
In fact. I would suggest that our listening is the main way
[AI] 事实上我认为我们的倾听是主要的方式
that we experience the flow of time from past to future.
[AI] 我们经历了从过去到未来的时间流。
So. "Sonority is time and meaning" -- a great quote.
[AI] 所以“响亮就是时间和意义”——一句名言。
I said at the beginning. we're losing our listening.
[AI] 我一开始就说了。我们失去了听力。
Why did I say that?
[AI] 我为什么这么说？
Well. there are a lot of reasons for this.
[AI] 好这有很多原因。
First of all. we invented ways of recording --
[AI] 首先我们发明了录音的方法--
first writing. then audio recording and now video recording as well.
[AI] 第一次写作。然后是录音，现在是录像。
The premium on accurate and careful listening has simply disappeared.
[AI] 准确、仔细倾听的优势已经消失。
Secondly. the world is now so noisy.
[AI] 其次现在的世界太吵了。
(Noise) with this cacophony going on visually and auditorily.
[AI] （噪音）这种杂音在视觉上和听觉上持续。
it's just hard to listen;
[AI] 只是很难倾听；
it's tiring to listen.
[AI] 听太累了。
Many people take refuge in headphones.
[AI] 许多人以耳机为避难所。
but they turn big. public spaces like this.
[AI] 但是它们变大了。像这样的公共空间。
shared soundscapes.
[AI] 共享音景。
into millions of tiny. little personal sound bubbles.
[AI] 成百万的微小的。小小的个人声音泡泡。
In this scenario. nobody's listening to anybody.
[AI] 在这种情况下。没人在听别人说话。
We're becoming impatient.
[AI] 我们变得不耐烦了。
We don't want oratory anymore; we want sound bites.
[AI] 我们不再需要雄辩；我们想要声音片段。
And the art of conversation is being replaced -- dangerously. I think --
[AI] 谈话的艺术正在被取代——危险地。我想--
by personal broadcasting.
[AI] 通过个人广播。
I don't know how much listening there is in this conversation.
[AI] 我不知道这段对话中有多少听众。
which is sadly very common. especially in the UK.
[AI] 不幸的是，这是非常普遍的。尤其是在英国。
We're becoming desensitized.
[AI] 我们变得不敏感了。
Our media have to scream at us with these kinds of headlines
[AI] 我们的媒体不得不用这样的标题对我们大喊大叫
in order to get our attention.
[AI] 为了引起我们的注意。
And that means it's harder for us to pay attention
[AI] 这意味着我们更难集中注意力
to the quiet. the subtle. the understated.
[AI] 安静下来。微妙的。这个问题被低估了。
This is a serious problem that we're losing our listening.
[AI] 这是一个严重的问题，我们正在失去听力。
This is not trivial.
[AI] 这不是小事。
because listening is our access to understanding.
[AI] 因为倾听是我们获得理解的途径。
Conscious listening always creates understanding.
[AI] 有意识的倾听总是创造理解。
and only without conscious listening
[AI] 只有在没有意识倾听的情况下
can these things happen.
[AI] 这些事情会发生吗。
A world where we don't listen to each other at all
[AI] 一个我们根本不听对方话的世界
is a very scary place indeed.
[AI] 这确实是一个非常可怕的地方。
So I'd like to share with you five simple exercises.
[AI] 所以我想和大家分享五个简单的练习。
tools you can take away with you.
[AI] 你可以随身携带的工具。
to improve your own conscious listening.
[AI] 提高你自己的有意识倾听。
Would you like that?
[AI] 你喜欢吗？
Audience: Yes!
[AI] 观众：是的！
Good. The first one is silence.
[AI] 好的第一个是沉默。
Just three minutes a day of silence is a wonderful exercise
[AI] 每天三分钟的沉默是一种很好的锻炼
to reset your ears and to recalibrate.
[AI] 重置你的耳朵并重新校准。
so that you can hear the quiet again.
[AI] 这样你就可以再次听到宁静。
If you can't get absolute silence.
[AI] 如果你不能得到绝对的沉默。
go for quiet. that's absolutely fine.
[AI] 保持安静。那太好了。
Second. I call this "the mixer."
[AI] 第二我称之为“混合器”
(Noise) So even if you're in a noisy environment like this --
[AI] （噪音）所以即使你处在这样一个嘈杂的环境中--
and we all spend a lot of time in places like this --
[AI] 我们都花了很多时间在这样的地方--
listen in the coffee bar to how many channels of sound can I hear?
[AI] 在咖啡馆里听，我能听到多少声道的声音？
How many individual channels in that mix am I listening to?
[AI] 我要听多少个单独的频道？
You can do it in a beautiful place as well. like in a lake.
[AI] 你也可以在一个美丽的地方做。就像在湖里一样。
How many birds am I hearing?
[AI] 我听到了多少只鸟？
Where are they? Where are those ripples?
[AI] 他们在哪里？那些涟漪在哪里？
It's a great exercise for improving the quality of your listening.
[AI] 这是提高听力质量的一个很好的练习。
Third. this exercise I call "savoring." and this is a beautiful exercise.
[AI] 第三这个练习我称之为“品味”这是一个很好的练习。
It's about enjoying mundane sounds.
[AI] 这是关于享受平凡的声音。
This. for example. is my tumble dryer.
[AI] 这例如这是我的滚筒式烘干机。
(Dryer) It's a waltz --
[AI] （干衣机）这是华尔兹--
one. two. three; one. two. three; one. two. three.
[AI] 一二三一二三一二三
I love it!
[AI] 我喜欢！
Or just try this one on for size.
[AI] 或者试试这个尺码。
(Coffee grinder)
[AI] （咖啡研磨机）
Wow!
[AI] 哇！
So. mundane sounds can be really interesting -- if you pay attention.
[AI] 所以如果你注意的话，平凡的声音会很有趣。
I call that the "hidden choir" -- it's around us all the time.
[AI] 我称之为“隐藏的唱诗班”——它一直在我们身边。
The next exercise is probably the most important of all of these.
[AI] 下一个练习可能是所有这些练习中最重要的。
if you just take one thing away.
[AI] 如果你只拿走一件东西。
This is listening positions --
[AI] 这是听力位置--
the idea that you can move your listening position
[AI] 你可以移动你的听力位置的想法
to what's appropriate to what you're listening to.
[AI] 对你正在听的内容进行适当的调整。
This is playing with those filters.
[AI] 这是在玩那些过滤器。
Remember I gave you those filters?
[AI] 还记得我给你的那些过滤器吗？
It's starting to play with them as levers.
[AI] 它开始把它们当作杠杆。
to get conscious about them and to move to different places.
[AI] 去了解他们，去不同的地方。
These are just some of the listening positions.
[AI] 这些只是一些倾听的姿势。
or scales of listening positions. that you can use.
[AI] 或听音位置的比例。你可以用的。
There are many.
[AI] 有很多。
Have fun with that. It's very exciting.
[AI] 祝你玩得开心。非常激动人心。
And finally. an acronym.
[AI] 最后。缩写词。
You can use this in listening. in communication.
[AI] 你可以用这个来听。在交流中。
If you're in any one of those roles --
[AI] 如果你担任这些角色中的任何一个--
and I think that probably is everybody who's listening to this talk --
[AI] 我想可能是每个人都在听这个演讲--
the acronym is RASA.
[AI] 首字母缩略词是RASA。
which is the Sanskrit word for "juice" or "essence."
[AI] 哪一个是梵文中“果汁”或“精华”的意思
And RASA stands for "Receive."
[AI] RASA代表“接收”
which means pay attention to the person;
[AI] 也就是说要注意人；
"Appreciate." making little noises like "hmm." "oh." "OK";
[AI] “谢谢。”发出像“嗯”“哦”这样的小声音“好”；
"Summarize" -- the word "so" is very important in communication;
[AI] “总结”——“所以”一词在交流中非常重要；
and "Ask." ask questions afterwards.
[AI] 和“问”事后提问。
Now sound is my passion. it's my life.
[AI] 现在声音是我的激情。这是我的生活。
I wrote a whole book about it. So I live to listen.
[AI] 我为此写了一整本书。所以我活着就是为了倾听。
That's too much to ask for most people.
[AI] 对大多数人来说，这要求太高了。
But I believe that every human being needs to listen consciously
[AI] 但我相信每个人都需要有意识地倾听
in order to live fully --
[AI] 为了活得充实--
connected in space and in time to the physical world around us.
[AI] 在空间和时间上与我们周围的物质世界相连。
connected in understanding to each other.
[AI] 在理解上相互联系。
not to mention spiritually connected.
[AI] 更不用说精神上的联系了。
because every spiritual path I know of has listening and contemplation
[AI] 因为我所知道的每一条精神之路都有倾听和沉思
at its heart.
[AI] 在它的核心。
That's why we need to teach listening in our schools as a skill.
[AI] 这就是为什么我们需要在学校教授听力作为一种技能。
Why is it not taught? It's crazy.
[AI] 为什么不教呢？这太疯狂了。
And if we can teach listening in our schools.
[AI] 如果我们能在学校里教听力。
we can take our listening off that slippery slope
[AI] 我们可以把我们的听力从那个滑坡上移开
to that dangerous. scary world that I talked about.
[AI] 去那危险的地方。我说的可怕的世界。
and move it to a place where everybody is consciously listening all the time.
[AI] 把它移到一个每个人都在有意识地倾听的地方。
or at least capable of doing it.
[AI] 或者至少有能力做到这一点。
Now. I don't know how to do that.
[AI] 现在我不知道怎么做。
but this is TED.
[AI] 但这是特德。
and I think the TED community is capable of anything.
[AI] 我认为TED社区可以做任何事情。
So I invite you to connect with me. connect with each other.
[AI] 所以我邀请你和我联系。相互联系。
take this mission out. And let's get listening taught in schools.
[AI] 完成这项任务。让我们在学校里学习听力。
and transform the world in one generation
[AI] 在一代人的时间里改变世界
to a conscious. listening world -- a world of connection.
[AI] 有意识地。倾听的世界——一个连接的世界。
a world of understanding and a world of peace.
[AI] 一个理解的世界，一个和平的世界。
Thank you for listening to me today.
[AI] 谢谢你今天听我说。
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）